Arunkumar V

Email: arunkumarv31@gmail.com Phone: +91-97908-46755

Website: arunkumarv.github.io

Professional Summary

Versatile software engineer with 12 years experience in developing software/embedded products for various government/private organisations. My career mission has been to work with thriving people/organisations to make software products that help people lead better lives.

Languages

JavaScript, C, Python, PHP, HTML, SQL, Dart, Java

Experience

Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (Chennai, India)

Principal Engineer

Jan 2019 - Present

- Developed a portal for monitoring candidate behaviour, anomaly detection and centre delay in near realtime during CAT exam. Client: Indian Air Force, Utilised: MEAN Stack.
- Built a web platform that enables NBA to perform regulatory functions against any noncompliance. Developed visualisations & maps for taxonomy, patent/journals search & filter system, e-filing reviewer. Client: National Biodiversity Authority.
- Designed & implemented front ends of SCRB portal. It has accused search & filter, timelines, crimes trends visualisations. Utilised: jQuery, VueJS, ChartJS.
- Created a wrapper for Imapsync (perl) to migrate mails from Gmail to CUTN servers.
- Implemented front ends for covid19 dashboard. Utilised: Leaflet, Bhuvan Maps, jQuery.
- Customised ReactJs modules for a maritime ship tracking software.

Senior Engineer

Jan 2013 - Jan 2019

- Implemented new features for CDAC's Project Accounting System. Utilised: AngularJS.
- Developed a dashboard for GCC. It has grievance redressal, revenue, ambulance tracking & air quality modules. Utilised. ExpressJs, Charts.
- Overhauled poorly designed user interfaces of Mess Management System (Navodaya School), designed wireframes & implemented pages in HTML/CSS.
- Developed the ethernet/WiFi interface of Smart plug. Implemented a scheduler. avr-gcc, Java, RN171, Atmega2560/328, W5100, CADSTAR. Deployed at HPC Facilities, Pune.

Engineer

Nov 2008 - Jan 2012

- Designed dimmable ballasts for CFLs and LED drivers for dimple LEDs. Utilised: CADSTAR
- Worked on a research project called Instrument bed. It aims at unobtrusive monitoring of respiratory signals & pulse using high sensitive load cells.

Kerala State Electricity Board (Ernakulam, Kerala)

Substation assistant

Sep 2007 - Oct 2007

 Collected daily meter readings, attended consumers complaints & reported to the duty engineer/line worker.

Personal Works

- As a hobbyist programmer, I develops things that others uses. Details at my Website.
- Context Aware Framework Java RMI, Malayalam dictionary Flask & SQLAlchemy, Browser extensions for Malayalam dictionary - javaScript, A basic scheduler for AVR.

Education

University of Kerala, Amrita Vishwa Vidya Peetham

2003 - 2007

Electronics & Communications (GPA: 6.5), Project: Encrypted wireless walkie talkie.

ER&DC, CDAC, Trivandrum, Kerala

2008 (6 months)

PG Diploma in Embedded System Design, Subjects: Data Structures, C, AVR, Algorithms.

Model Technical Higher Secondary School, Kaprassery, Kerala

1998 - 2003

Subject: Electronics, Electrical, C, BASIC, FORTRAN,

Frameworks

Angular, Express.js, Node.js, Flutter , Hapi.js, jQuery, Flask

Concepts

Object Oriented Design & Development, Entity Relationship Diagram, UML

Software/Platform

Mongo, Pg/MySQL, git, gcc, ELK, Apache, Firebase, LAMP, CADSTAR, VSCode, Vim, Android

Systems

Mac, Ubuntu, Windows